Hello, I am Mohammed Elagouz, a UX designer based in Austin, TX. For the past 10 years I have been designing for the human experience, from digital interfaces to living spaces and urban planning. I love a creative challenge, and design thinking is one of my strengths. My core principles are integrity and compassion. I work smart and I do my best to see the positive side of complicated situations in order to amplify and reflect it.

WHAT I DO: My training as a UX designer and experience working in the startup environment has taught me how to develop and manage the entire user experience from start to finish. I excel at translating research data into interactions through:

- Ideation from concept maps, user flows, system diagrams and navigation systems, to running design studios, sketching and storyboarding.
- Developing prototypes, lo-fi wireframes and hi-fi UI/mockups.
- Prototyping with HTML/CSS/jQuery (I'm also exploring prototyping with xCode). I'm early adopter of new technology and love learning new things everyday.
- User testing to validate my ideas.
- Iterating my designs based the test results.

Also, having an experience in designing living spaces as an architectural designer dovetails perfectly with my passion to work with IOT and VR design.

Experience

UX DESIGNER, IBM; AUSTIN, TEXAS - 2016-PRESENT

Part of marketing and sales organization. I worked on designing a digital enablement tools and experience for IBM sellers. I also worked on training new IBMers (designers and marketers) on IBM Design thinking and Agile.

UX/UI DESIGNER, MOWDO: SEATTLE, WASHINGTON - 2015

Designing a better on-boarding process and app flow for a B2C start up during 9milesLab Startup accelerator. I also filled for other rolls when needed to. Deliverables: sketches & wireframes, prototypes, usability testing insights, high fidelity design mock-ups, affinity diagrams, user personas, site maps, style guides.

UX/UI DESIGNER, HRS; SEATTLE, WASHINGTON - 2015

As a part of project pro bono and Working with a team of three UX Designers. I developed an app raising awareness about human rights issues for HRS in Seattle. Role: Interaction design, UI design, prototyping, User testing and research Deliverables: User Research, persona development, User flows/stories/scenarios, Interaction design, Prototyping, Wireframes, User Testing, Visual design, Site maps, Style guide, Sketches & Wireframes, High fidelity design mock-ups and Affinity diagrams.

FREELANCER DESIGNER, MULTIPLE CLIENTS; SEATTLE, WASHINGTON - 2013-2010

Helped some local commerce to establish a present online from landing pages to blogs. Also worked with senior designers and web designer intern on redesign a local interior designer -musadesign- website and branding.

ARCHITECT, MULTIPLE CLIENTS; CAIRO, EGYPT - 2010-2007

I was involved in programing, project management, value engineering and construction working drawings. The main projects I worked on are; - Producing CD's for a winning competition proposal for a land mark monument in Al-Damaam Saudi Arabia. - A Design Proposal [shortlisted] for Qatari government for a multiple mosques projects. We were so close to win, the Qatari Gov. loved the design proposal, but our office was too small to be granted a big contract. - Producing Architecture Design, Programing and CD's for a Hi-rise and Mid-rise building complex. - Project management for several residential projects in Cairo, Egypt.

Education

Modern Academy for engineering and technology – Architecture, BSc. - 2002-2007

General Assembly – User experience design immersive - 2015 Code fellows – Front-End foundation II - 2014 School of Visual Concepts – User experience for Mobile Device - 2014

Sills

Professional Skills:

Design Thinking | Interaction Design | User Research, Personas and Scenarios | User Flows, Journeys & Stories | Use Case | Sketching | Usability Testing | Task Analysis | Heuristics | Site Maps | Rapid Prototyping | Information Architecture | Project Management | Concept Generation | Typography | Visual Design | Sitemaps | Storyboarding | Navigation System

Professional Tools:

HTML, CSS & jQuery | Sketch App | Axure | Marvel App | InVision | Git&Github | Photoshop | Pen & Paper | Command Line | 3D Studio Max |